<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home on Val Baturin&#39;s Personal Pages</title>
    <link>http://baturin.me/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home on Val Baturin&#39;s Personal Pages</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 05 Feb 2019 07:51:49 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://baturin.me/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>What is RPC for real</title>
      <link>http://baturin.me/posts/what_is_rpc/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2020 18:43:24 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://baturin.me/posts/what_is_rpc/</guid>
      <description>Before you get started I assume that a fellow reader has some understanding of APIs and experience with REST, in particular, might help as well. The goal of this post is to provide a clear understanding of RPC. You might&#39;ve already worked with gRPC or Apache Thrift but still can&#39;t elaborate on the differences between REST API and the mentioned tech. This post is exactly for you.
How to deal with new knowledge Math teaches us before we&#39;re working with some kind abstraction we&#39;d better have a formal definition of that thing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Arch is stable</title>
      <link>http://baturin.me/posts/arch_is_stable/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2020 17:32:24 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://baturin.me/posts/arch_is_stable/</guid>
      <description>As you might notice after reading the about me page, I have the macbook and don&#39;t run macos. It&#39;s not a popular choice and folks around keep saying that macos is unix or unix-like system and has everything you need including tools for development pursope. It&#39;s kinda true and most of the tools are available. Despite of that I faced a number of issues with software not being able to compile for macos on macos.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>http://baturin.me/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2020 15:02:47 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://baturin.me/about/</guid>
      <description>Occupation Computer Science student at Higher School of Economics, Moscow
Interests in no particular order  Programming languages and compilers Linguistics Type theory Operating systems Smartphones Software architecture design Client-side Consensus algorithms  My machine MBP 13-inch i5 Early 2015 with replaced stock SSD to Samsung SSD 970 PRO
Arch Linux distribution
Software of choice and their configuration sway, termite, tmux (default configuration), neovim</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>http://baturin.me/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2019 10:59:56 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://baturin.me/contact/</guid>
      <description> GitHub &amp;ndash; Hit that follow button val@baturin.me &amp;ndash; Personal email val.baturin@serokell.io &amp;ndash; Haskell consulting LinkedIn &amp;ndash; Just in case  </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>